Finding Aid for the Mackenzie Bell Papers LSC.0705
UCLA Library Special Collections
Mackenzie Bell papers
1860-1930
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bell, Mackenzie
LSC.0705
1 unknown (14 boxes and 4 oversize boxes)
Mackenzie Bell (1856-1930) published numerous books, articles and poems. The collection contains holograph manuscripts, notebooks, correspondence, pictures, and related ephemera. Includes holograph manuscripts of Spring's Immortality and Other Poems, Pictures of Travel and Other Poems, and William Morris, Poet and Socialist, as I Knew Him. Also contains materials relating to the Rossettis, Algernon Swinburne, Theodore Watts-Dunton, William Morris, and Charles Whitehead.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Purchssed from W.P. Wreden, 1962, 1975. Purchased from Winifred Myers, 1964.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303653606533
Biography
Mackenzie Bell was born in 1856 in Liverpool, England; he settled in London in 1884; the same year saw the publication of his book, Charles Whitehead: A Forgotten Genius; wrote critical articles for Academy, Speaker, Temple Bar and other publications; became a member of the Reform Club; other published works include Verses of Varied Life (1882), Spring's Immortality: and Other Poems (1893), and Christina Rossetti: A Biographical and Critical Study; he died in 1930.
Scope and Content
Collection contains holograph manuscripts, notebooks, correspondence, pictures, and related ephemera. Includes holograph manuscript of Spring's Immortality and Other Poems, Pictures of Travel and Other Poems, and William Morris, Poet and Socialist, as I Knew Him. Also contains author's copy of collected poems, books about Christina Rossetti and Charles Whitehead, and a typescript of Swinburne and his poetry, with holographs of William Morris. Also contains materials relating to the Rossettis, Algernon Swinburne, Theodore Watts-Dunton, William Morris, and Charles Whitehead.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Manuscripts and first editions of poems.
Author's copy of his books on Christina Rossetti and Charles Whitehead, and typescript of book on Algernon Charles Swinburne.
Miscellaneous manuscripts, photographs and ephemera.
Illustrations, etchings and reproductions.
Correspondence.
Items removed from Collection
Morris, William, 1834-1896--Portrait. See Related Material.
Related Material
Picture Collection (Collection 99). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Collier, John. Richard Garnett. [London (?), ca. 1900] Photograph, mounted. (In Coll. ORIG. 99) 1 item. 22.5 × 18cm.
Manuscripts for publication; Poets, English -- Archives.; Authors, English -- Archives.; Bell, Mackenzie, 1856-1930--Archives.
- Spring's Immortality. Published by Ward, Lock, and Bowden, Limited, London, 1895.; 2 different copies. (Box 5)
  Scope and Contents note
  Author's copy. 2nd edition with some holograph revisions in preparation for next edition.
- Spring's Immortality and Other Poems. n.p., Holograph manuscript. Bound in blue cloth. (Box 18)
- Poems. Working copy vol.16. Published by Clark, London, 1909.; In original blue covers. (Box 1)
  Author's copy with programs, brochures, letters, notes, etc. attached and inserted throughout book.
- Collected Poems., In original lavender covers. (Box 1)
  Author's copy with holograph annotations and letters, notes, miscellaneous ephemera attached and inserted throughout book. First page lists poems that have been recited.
- Manuscript of poems between 1898 and 1909. n.p., Bound in half calf and green cloth covers. (Box 14)
  Mostly holograph with pages of typescript, annotated proofs of published poems, and newspaper and magazine clippings of his published poems and articles with holograph notations, interspersed.
- Pictures Of Travel and Other Poems., Holograph. Bound in green calf. (Box 3)
- Pictures of Travel and Other Poems., Typescript with holograph corrections. 76 leaves. (Box 7)
  First leaf reads To a worker among the poor and other poems with final title penciled in below.
- Pictures of Travel and Other Poems., 23 sheets plus preliminary pages. (Box 7)
  Corrected galleys.
- Pictures of Travel and Other Poems. Published by Hurst and Blackett Limited, London, 1898. (Box 7)
  Author's copy. Occasional holograph corrections.
- Pictures of Travel and Other Poems., 6 copies of book. (Box 5)
- Christina Rossetti. Published by Hurst and Blackett Limited, London, 1898.; Binding lacking. (Box 5)
  Author's copy with copious holograph notes in ink, in preparation for revised edition. Note to the printer on first leaf.
- Notebooks., 4 items. Mostly bound in half calf and marbled boards. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)
  Diaries with occasional letters and miscellaneous pieces of ephemera inserted.
  - 1., February 20, 1897-July 12, 1897. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)
  - 2., November 4, 1890-April 4, 1891. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)
  - 3., May 9, 1884-April 15 1885. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)
  - 4., January 5, 1880-November 22, 1880. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)
- A Forgotten Genius: Charles Whitehead. London, Elliot Stock, 1884.; Unbound. Most of the pages are cut into three parts and mounted separately on white paper. (Box 4)
  Author's copy.
- Extract from an article about Whitehead by James Smith.... Holograph copy from direct transfer. Published in The Australian, July 28, 1894.; 22 leaves. (Box 4)
- Swinburne and his Poetry. n.p., 208 leaves, Unbound. (Box 7)
  Typescipt with minor corrections.
- School Recitations. London: James Clark & Company, 1909.; 2 copies. (Box 5)
- Poems of Nature. London: James Clark & Company, 6 copies. (Box 5)
- Poems of Consolation and of Religion. London: James Clark & Company, 5 copies. (Box 5)
- Trafalgar. Kingsgate Press, London, [1913].; 24 copies. (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous incomplete manuscripts., Typescript and mimeograph with corrections. 3 items. (Box 6)
- Notes, miscellaneous, mostly holograph., 14 items. In mixed order. (Box 7)
  Includes short, incomplete manuscripts of articles, poems, etc., and some corrected and revised printed matter.
- Ephemera., 49 items. (Box 7)
  Newspaper clippings, magazine articles, pamphlets, brochures, broadsides etc.
- Engraved steel blocks of The Heart's Summer, Holy Quietude, and Lyrics of Consolation., Mounted on wood. 3 items. (Box 5)
- Framed photograph of Mackenzie Bell and his sister Mary Elizabeth and Maggie, dated, 1863. (Box 5)
- Photographs of friends and acquaintances including prominent literary figures etc., 2 envelopes, 36 items. (Box 4)
- Christmas cards to Bell., 45 pieces. (Box 5)
- Illustrations for Christina Rossetti. Mounted reproductiohs of drawings etc., 6 items. (Box 2)
- Original ink sketches for Pictures of Travel., 6 items. (Box 6)
- Two framed, original etchings by Dante Gabriel Rossetti, 1894 and one framed reproduction of poem by Theodore Watts-Dunton,, presented and signed by Watts-Dunton to Bell., 1891 (Box 15)
- Three mounted and one framed reproductions of drawings and paintings owned by Christina Rossetti until her death. (Box 15, Box 16)
  Also: one mounted photograph of her funeral, all presented to Bell by William Rossetti.
  Also: photograph of family grave given to M.B. from Lisa Wilson. January 6, 1898.
- Miscellaneous reproductions and photographs., 5 items. (Box 15)
- Framed oil sketck of William MacDonald Sinclair by William Lockhart, 1887. (Box 17)
- Reminiscences of Liszt, by George Liebling., Holograph manuscript in pencil. 29 leaves. (Box 6)
  Written on Back of identical mimeographed publicity letters announcing Liebling's availability for the coming concert season and signed by his secretary, January 1900.
- William Morris, Poet and Socialist, as I Knew Him. n.p., Holograph and mimeograph with extensive ink notations.; 56 leaves.
- Three pages of proof corrected in ink.
  With attached note: "Some sheets of Mrs. Henry Wood's Dene Hollow given to me at my request by Dr. Japp, September 15, 1893."
- Correspondence and related ephemera from friends and literary figures, mostly addressed to Bell., 1851-1931.; 844 items. (Box 8, Box 9)
  General note
  Added entries listed below:
- Correspondence and documents for the year 1891, with a few letters dated, 1890, 1892, 1893, and 1894.; 300 items. (Box 10)
  Much of this material relates to the death of Bell's mother in 1891. Correspondents include Douglas Sladen and Theodore Watts-Dunton.
  Also included are copies of Bell's letters.
  Separate purchase from Winifred Myers, London, August 1964.
- List of Correspondents:
  - Adams, William Davenport, 1851-1904. (Box 8)
  - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey, 1836-1907. (Box 8)
  - Allen, Grant, 1848-1899. (Box 8)
  - Anderson, Jessie Annie. (Box 8)
  - Austin, Alfred, 1835-1913. (Box 8)
  - Bainton, George. (Box 8)
  - Bayley, Ada Ellen, 1857-1903. (Box 8)
  - Beaton, Rev. Patrick. (Box 8)
  - Bennett, William Henry, 1855-1920. (Box 8)
  - Bentley, George, 1828-1895. (Box 8)
  - Besant, Sir Walter, 1836-1901. (Box 8)
  - Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927. (Box 8)
  - Black, William, 1841-1898. (Box 8)
  - Broadbent, Albert. (Box 8)
  - Brotherton, Mrs. Mary Isabella Irwin. (Box 8)
  - Brown, Mrs. Mary Chadwick (Barrett) 1827-1887. (Box 8)
  - Bruce, Mary Louisa. (Box 8)
  - Bryan, Alfred. (Box 8)
  - Cable, Louise. (Box 8)
  - Cable, George Washington, 1844-1925. (Box 8)
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910. (Box 8)
  - Crawford, Francis Marion, 1854-1909. (Box 8)
  - Crockett, Samuel Rutherford, 1860-1914. (Box 8)
  - Cross, Frederick J. (Box 8)
  - Crowe, Eyre, 1824-1910. (Box 8)
  - Curtis, Albert Charles, 1867-. (Box 8)
  - De Vere, Aubrey Thomas, 1814-1902. (Box 8)
  - Dibdin, Edward Rimbault, 1853-. (Box 8)
  - Dibdin, Sir Robert William, 1848-. (Box 8)
  - Duckworth, Francis Robinson Gladstone. (Box 8)
  - Fawcett, Edgar, 1847-1904. (Box 8)
  - Fildes, Sir Luke, 1844-1927. (Box 8)
  - Fisher, Frederic Henry, 1849-1926. (Box 8)
  - Fitzpatrick, William John, 1830-1895. (Box 8)
  - Fletcher, James, 1852-1908. (Box 8)
  - Gissing, Algernon. (Box 8)
  - Green, James, 1841-1926. (Box 8)
  - Hake, Guy Donne Gordon, 1887-. (Box 8)
    [letter to Bell written at age 6]
  - Harraden, Beatrice, 1864-. (Box 8)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894. (Box 8)
  - Hunt, Edith Holman Hunt. (Box 8)
  - Hutchinson, Thomas. (Box 8)
  - Hyatt, Alfred H. (Box 8)
  - Jerrold, Walter Copeland, 1865-1929. (Box 8)
  - Lee, Arthur Hamilton Lee, viscount, 1868-. (Box 8)
  - Lee, Sir, Sydney, 1859-1926. (Box 8)
  - Leighton, Marie (Connor) d. 1941. (Box 8)
  - Liebling, George. (Box 8)
  - Lloyd, Charles Ellis, d. 1939. (Box 8)
  - Locker-Lampson, Frederick, 1821-1895. (Box 8)
  - Matheson, Annie, 1853-. (Box 8)
  - Maxwell, John, 1824-1895. (Box 8)
  - Meynell, Alice (Thompson). (Box 8)
  - Miles, Alfred Henry, 1848-. (Box 8)
  - Morris, William, 1834-1896. (Box 8)
    (Includes 2 photographs of Morris)
    [See items removed from collection]
  - Nisbett, Hume, 1850-1923. (Box 9)
  - Pole, William, 1814-1900. (Box 9)
  - Rossetti, William Michael, 1829-1919. (Box 9)
  - Sambourne, Edwin Linley, 1844-1910. (Box 9)
  - Shields, Frederic James, 1833-1911. (Box 9)
  - Shorthouse, Joseph Henry, 1834-1903. (Box 9)
  - Sladen, Douglas Brooke Wheelton, 1856-. (Box 9)
  - Smith, Albert, 1860-. (Box 9)
  - Sonnenschein, William Swan, 1855-1931. (Box 9)
  - Stoker, Bram, 1847-1912. (Box 9)
  - Swanwick, Anna, 1813-1899. (Box 9)
  - Tennyson Family. (Box 9)
  - Thomas, Henry, 1878-. (Box 9)
  - Thompson, Augustus Charles, 1812-1901. (Box 9)
  - Thornley, James L. (Box 9)
  - Thornton, J. (Box 9)
  - Walford, Mrs. Lucy Bethia (Colquhoun) 1845-1915. (Box 9)
  - Walton, Sir John, 1852-1908. (Box 9)
  - Watts-Dunton, Walter Theodore, 1832-1914. (Box 9)
  - Waugh, Arthur, 1866-1943. (Box 9)
  - Westall, William, 1835-1903. (Box 9)
  - Whiteing, Richard, 1840-1928. (Box 9)
  - Williamson, David, 1868-. (Box 9)
  - Wright, Charles Theodore Hagberg, 1862-. (Box 9)
  - Wright, Sydney Fowler, 1874-. (Box 9)
  - Young, Sir Frederick, 1817-1913. (Box 9)
- Correspondence of the Rossetti Family:
  - Christina Georgina, 1830-1894. (Box 9)
  - Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882. (Box 9)
  - Frances. (Box 9)
  - Gabriele Pasquale Giuseppe, 1783-1854. (Box 9)
  - Maria Francesca, 1827-1876. (Box 9)
  - William Michael, 1829-1919. (Box 9)
- Correspondence re Mackenzie Bell's book, Christina Rossetti., 89 items. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence re Mackenzie Bell's book, Christina Rossetti., 24 items. (Box 9)
    Adams, William Davenport, 1851-1904.
    Adams, Mrs. Estelle (Körner) Davenport
    Anderson, John Parker, 1841-.
    Blaikie, William Garden, 1820-1899.
  - Correspondence re Mackenzie Bell's book, Christina Rossetti, 26 items. (Box 9)
    Dixon, Richard Watson, 1833-1900.
    Dowden, Edward, 1843-1913.
    Fairbairn, Andrew Martin, 1838-1912.
    Fletcher, Alfred Ewen, 1841-1915.
    Gosse, Edmund William, 1849-1928.
    Greenwood, Frederick, 1830-1909.
    Gurney, Alfred, 1845-1898.
  - Correspondence re Mackenzie Bell's book, Christina Rossetti., 12 items. (Box 9)
    Horder, William Garrett, 1841-1922.
    Hughes, Arthur, 1832-1915.
    Hunt, William Holman, 1827-1910.
  - Correspondence re Mackenzie Bell's book, Christina Rossetti., 9 items. (Box 9)
    Ingram, John H., 1849-1916.
    Jenks, George C.
    Kernahan, Coulson, 1858-1943.
    Kernahan, Mary Jane Hickling (Gwynne) Mrs. Coulson Kernahan, 1857-.
  - Correspondence re Mackenzie Bell's book, Christina Rossetti., 9 items. (Box 9)
    Lang, Andrew, 1844-1912.
    Leighton, Robert, 1859-.
    Lobb, John, 1840-1921.
    Low, Sir Sidney James Mark, 1857-1932.
  - Correspondence re Mackenzie Bell's book, Christina Rossetti., folder P-W: 8 items. (Box 9)
    Webster, Thomas, 1809-1901.
- Correspondence re Mackenzie Bell's book, Charles Whitehead. (Box 9)
  - Blanchard, Edward Litt Laman, 1820-1889. (Box 9)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard, 1866-1947. (Box 9)
  - Pearson, Sir Cyril Arthur, 1866-1921. (Box 9)
  - Pollard, Alfred William, 1859-1944. (Box 9)
  - Tristram, William Outram. (Box 9)
  - Wright, Thomas, 1810-1877. (Box 9)
  - Sladen, Douglas Brooke Wheelton, 1856-. (Box 9)
- Correspondence re the election of John Beattie Crozier, 1849-1921, to the Athenaeum Club, v.p., 1904.; 38 items. (Box 9)
  - Baird, Helen. (Box 9)
  - Brabrook, Sir Edward William, 1839-1930. (Box 9)
  - Bruce-Joy, Albert, d. 1924. (Box 9)
  - Collier, Robert Collier, 2nd. baron Monkswell, 1845-1909. (Box 9)
  - Collins, John Churton, 1848-1908. (Box 9)
  - Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921. (Box 9)
  - Dalton, Frederick Thomas, 1855-1927. (Box 9)
  - Fildes, Sir Luke, 1844-1927. (Box 9)
  - Gann, Frederick. (Box 9)
  - Gosse, Andrew. (Box 9)
  - Harley, Robert, 1828-1910. (Box 9)
  - Hawkins, Sir Anthony Hope, 1863-1933. (Box 9)
  - Irving, Sir Henry, 1838-1905. (Box 9)
  - Jacobs, William Wymark, 1863-. (Box 9)
  - Kinnaird, Arthur FitzGerald, 11th. baron, 1847-1923. (Box 9)
  - Lee, Sir Sidney, 1859-1926. (Box 9)
  - Levenson Gower, Arthur Francis Gesham, 1851-. (Box 9)
  - MacAlister, Sir Donald, 1854-1934. (Box 9)
  - Mackail, John William, 1859-. (Box 9)
  - MacColl, Norman, 1843-1904. (Box 9)
  - Marten, Sir Theodore, 1816-1909. (Box 9)
  - Munby, Arthur Joseph, 1828-1910. (Box 9)
  - Raleigh, Sir Thomas, 1850-1920. (Box 9)
  - Ritchie, Anne Isabella (Thackeray) lady, 1837-1919. (Box 9)
  - Scott, Margaret (Mrs. Clement Scott). (Box 9)
  - Sinclair, William MacDonald, 1850-1917. (Box 9)
  - Shorter, Clement King, 1857-1929. (Box 9)
  - Watkins, Henry William, 1844-1922. (Box 9)
  - Wolf. (Box 9)
- Morris, William, 1834-1896--Portrait. (Box 11)
  Removed from the Collection. See Related Material.
- Correspondence
  - A-G. v.p., v.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - [to unknown] from McKenzie Bell., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Adamson, Thomas L., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Caine, Hall., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - [to] Caine, Mary Hall., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Coates, M., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Crosby, Bell., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Darton, Mary., 13 items. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Divine, Walter., 4 items. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Gardner, Anne B., 9 items. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - H-M. v.p., v.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - International Institute of British Poetry., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - International Society of Literature, Science and Art., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Jones, Henry Arthur., 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Kernahan., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - King, Maria., 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Kirivan, Patrick., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - The League of Mercy., 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - M, A.P., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Martin, Lydia., 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Morgan, Olive., 5 items. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Hunt, C.T., 5 items. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Martin, William H., 27 items. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - N-Z. v.p., v.d. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Pointer, W.H., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Sallmann, Otto., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Society of Authors., 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - [to] Swinburne, Algernon Charles., (copy). 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Thoebold., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Webster, Alex., 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Williams, Fleetwood., 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Watson, Alexander., 8 items. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Shakespeare Globe Theatre Memorial., 4 items. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Statement of Bell's accounts., 5 items. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence re publication of a sonnet by McKenzie Bell., 13 items. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Account of expenditures., 4 items. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript notes in Bell's hand, 18 leaves., 1891. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Notes. v.p., v.d., Holograph. 21 leaves. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Ephemera., 17 items. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - King Lear: A Tragedy in Five Acts, by William Shakespeare, as arranged for the stage by Henry Irving, and presented at the Lyceum Theatre, on November 10, 1892. London, Nassau Steam Press, Limited (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - London Shakespeare League. Ephemera., 9 items. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Photographs of McKenzie Bell., 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Correspondence and Ephemera Regarding the London Shakespeare League Dinner on April 23, 1907
  (Arranged by McKenzie Bell)
  - Draft of invitation., 9 items. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Refusals to dinner, A-F., 18 items. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Refusals to dinner, G-K., 8 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Refusals to dinner, L-R., 11 items. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Refusals to dinner, S-Z., 13 items. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Requests for tickets, A-F., 22 items. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Requests for tickets, G-L., 27 items. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Requests for tickets, M-R., 18 items. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Requests for tickets, S-Z., 17 items. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Clippings., 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence re seating plan., 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Seating plan., 5 items. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Bell's program notes., Holograph. 11 l. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Guest list, notes, tickets., 11 items. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence with various persons re arrangements for London Shakespeare League dinner. n.p., 1907.; 37 items. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and advertisements re trade services., 11 items. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Publicity., 11 items. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Entertainment., 7 items. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Printing., 13 items. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Receipts., 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Addresses., 11 items. (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Clippings., 13 items. (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Clippings., 17 items. (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Programs., 12 items. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - "The Graphic Gallery" of Shakespeare's Heroines. London, Sampson, Low, Marston, Searle & Rivington, Limited, 1888.; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - With this advertisement., 1 item.
  - Ephemera., 22 items. (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - The Athenaeum, Pall Mall. Ephemera., 10 pieces. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - McKenzie Bell's manuscript notes regarding his candidacy for membership to the Athenaeum Club. v.d., 25 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Correspondence re Bell's Candidacy for Membership to the Athenaeum Club, 1901-1902
  - A - F., 24 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Anderson, S., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - [to] Archdeacon of London., 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Brabrook, Sir Edward William, 1839-1930., 3 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Brown, A. Theodore., 3 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bruce-Joy, Albert, d. 1924., 6 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Caine, W.S., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Collins, John Churton, 1848-1908., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - [to] De Vere, Aubrey Thomas, 1814-1902., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Dicksee, Sir Francis Bernard, 1853-., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921., 4 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Parrar, Frederick William, 1831-1903., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - G - L., 23 items. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Harley, Robert, 1828-1910., 19 items. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Hawkins, Sir Anthony Hope, 1863-1933., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Kinnaird, Arthur Fitzgerald, 11th baron, 1847-1923., 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Levenson Gower, Arthur Francis Gesham, 1851-., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - M - R., 8 items. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - MacAlister, Sir John Young Walker, 1856-1925., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - MacColl, Norman, 1843-1904., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - MacWhirter, J., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Morris, Sir Lewis, 1833-1907., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Munby, Arthur Joseph, 1828-1910., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Ritchie, Anne Isabella (Thackeray), lady, 1837-1919. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Ritchie, Richmond., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - S - Z., 20 items. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Scott, Clement William, 1841-1904., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Saunders, T Bailey., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Tedder, Henry Richard, 1850-1924., 11 items. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - [to] Tennyson, Lord Alfred., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Tristram, H.N. (?), 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Watkins, Henry William, 1844-1922., 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Young, Sir Frederick, 1817-1913., 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified., 22 items (5 leaves, 17 envelopes). (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1921.; 3 items (5 leaves). (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified. (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Manuscript of poems between 1898 and 1909., Bound in half calf and green cloth covers. (Box 14)
  Mostly holograph with pages of typescript, annotated proofs of published poems, and newspaper and magazine clippings of his published poems and articles with holograph notations interspersed.
- Various etchings, reproductions of drawings and paintings, and photographs. (Box 15)
  See above for complete list.
- One framed reproduction of painting owned by Christina Rossetti until her death. Portrait of Beethoven. Photograph of a port town. (Box 16)